richersounds.com 2017-03-19

# Richer Sounds - The UK's Hi-Fi, Home Cinema & TV Specialists!

This privacy policy applies only to www.richersounds.com

Richer Sounds also includes Empire Direct.co.uk. This privacy policy explains how RS Plc uses the information it collects about you and procedures that RS Plc has in place to safeguard your privacy.

Richer Sounds Plc ("RS Plc") is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Under the Data Protection Act 1998 RS Plc has a legal duty to protect any personal information it collects from you.

What information do we collect about you?  
RS Plc does not capture and store any personal information about an individual who accesses this website, except where he or she voluntarily chooses to give RS Plc personal information via email, or by using an electronic form on the website, or by enquiring about any of RS Plc's services.

Cookies Policy  
**(a) What is a cookie?**  
A cookie is a small text file, which often includes a unique identifier that is sent to your computer or mobile phone (referred to here as a "device") browser from a website's computer and is stored on your device's hard drive. There are various types of cookies which perform different functions, such as remembering which items you have placed in your shopping basket or recording your browsing habits. The information recorded by the cookie is retrieved on the user's next visit to the site.   
For more information about cookies, visit [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/)

**(b) Richer Sounds cookies - how to manage cookies**  
Most web browsers will accept cookies, but if you would rather that we did not collect data in this way you can choose to accept all or some or reject cookies in your browser's privacy settings. Rejecting all cookies means that certain features cannot then be provided to you and accordingly you may not be able to take full advantage of all of the website's features and you may be prevented from completing your purchase online. Each browser is different, so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences.

**How to check cookies are enabled for PCs**

**Google Chrome**  
1\. Click on 'Tools' at the top of your browser window and select Options  
2\. Click the 'Under the Hood' tab, locate the 'Privacy' section, and select the 'Content settings' button  
3\. Now select 'Allow local data to be set' 

**Microsoft Internet Explorer 6.0, 7.0, 8.0**  
1\. Click on 'Tools' at the top of your browser window and select 'Internet options' , then click on the 'Privacy' tab  
2\. Ensure that your Privacy level is set to Medium or below, which will enable cookies in your browser  
3\. Settings above Medium will disable cookies

**Mozilla Firefox**  
1\. Click on 'Tools' at the top of your browser window and select Options  
2\. Then select the Privacy icon  
3\. Click on Cookies, then select 'allow sites to set cookies'

**Safari**  
1\. Click on the Cog icon at the top of your browser window and select the 'Preferences' option  
2\. Click on 'Security', check the option that says 'Block third-party and advertising cookies'  
3\. Click 'Save'

**How to check cookies are enabled for Macs**

**Google Chrome**  
1\. Click on 'Chrome' at the top of your browser window and select 'Preferences' options  
2\. Click the 'Under the Hood' tab, locate the 'Privacy' section, and select the 'Content settings' button  
3\. Now select 'Allow local data to be set'

**Safari**  
1\. Click on 'Safari' at the top of your browser window and select the 'Preferences' option  
2\. Click on 'Security' then 'Accept cookies'  
3\. Select the 'Only from site you navigate to'

**Mozilla Firefox**  
1\. Click on 'Firefox' at the top of your browser window and select 'Preferences' options  
2\. Then select the Privacy icon  
3\. Now select 'Accept cookies from sites'

**Microsoft Internet Explorer 5.0 on OSX**  
1\. Click on 'Explorer' at the top of your browser window and select 'Preferences' options  
2\. Scroll down until you see 'Cookies' under Receiving Files  
3\. Select the 'Never Ask' option

If your browser isn’t shown above, [click here](http://www.aboutcookies.org/how-to-control-cookies/).

If you want to delete any cookies that are already on your computer, please refer to the instructions for your file management software to locate the file or directory that stores cookies or [click here](http://www.aboutcookies.org/how-to-delete-cookies/).

**(c) How does Richer Sounds use cookies?**  
On richersounds.com, cookies record information about your online preferences, remember information about you when you visit our site and compile statistical reports on website activity. Some cookies are used that are essential in order to provide our services to you.

During the course of any visit to richersounds.com, your navigation through the site is recorded by a cookie that is downloaded to your device. The information recorded is retrieved on a repeat visit to the site by checking to see, and finding, the cookie left there on the last visit.

Information supplied by cookies can help us to analyse the profile of our visitors and help us to provide you with a better user experience. Below we have set out the four categories of cookies that Richer Sounds uses on our website. These cookies are: 

**• Strictly necessary cookies**  
These cookies are essential in order to enable you to move around the website and use its features, such as using the shopping basket to continue to navigate the site when making a purchase. Without these cookies, services you have asked for, such as making a purchase using the website, cannot be provided. These cookies do not gather information about you that could be used for marketing or remembering where you have been on the internet.

**• Performance cookies**  
These cookies collect information about how our visitors use the website, for instance which pages visitors go to most often, and if they get error messages from any web pages. They also allow us to record and count the number of visitors to the website, all of which enables us to see how visitors use the website in order to improve the way that our website works. These cookies do not collect information that identifies a visitor, as all information these cookies collect is anonymous and is only used to improve how our website works.

**• Functionality cookies**  
These cookies allow our website to remember choices you make (such as your login details or your choices in relation to our newsletter). Whenever these cookies are used we will notify you before using the cookie, providing more information about the functionality cookie to be used, and how it might improve your user experience. The information these cookies collect is usually anonymised. They do not gather any information about you that could be used for advertising or remember where you have been on the internet.

**• Targeting cookies**  
These cookies collect several pieces of information about your browsing habits. They are placed by our third party service provider [although we may also place a cookie that collects this kind of information]. All of the information that these cookies collect is anonymised, although they contain a unique key that is able to distinguish, for example, individual user browsing habits, or log if an individual user has clicked on a one of our suggested recommendations. These cookies can track your visits around the website, but they do not usually know who you are. They remember that you have visited our website and your browsing habits on our website to improve your experience, so that our recommendations are a better fit for you. This information is only shared between us and our third party service provider. Without these cookies, the recommendations you encounter and user experience on our website will be less relevant to you and your interests.

How will we use the information about you?  
We will collect information about you to process your order, manage your account and, if you agree, to email you about other products and services we think may be of interest to you.

We use your information collected from the website to personalise your repeat visits to our website. If you agree, we shall pass on your information to our group of companies so that they may offer you their products and services.

In these circumstances, any personal information supplied will only be used to provide the requested information or service unless wider purposes are specified in the form on which the information is supplied or at the point of collection on the website, in which case the information may be used for any of those wider purposes.

RS Plc may also use aggregate information and statistics for the purposes of monitoring website usage in order to help us develop the website and our services and may provide such aggregate information to third parties. These statistics will not include information that can be used to identify any individual.

RS Plc will only hold your information for as long as necessary for the purpose for which it was collected. RS Plc will not sell, distribute or disclose information about you or your personal usage of the website without your express consent or unless required to do so by law. If you subscribe to our mailing lists for new release and other information, we may also ask you to answer various general questions about yourself. You might be asked to specify the areas in which you are interested in so that we can tailor the information which we sent to you to cover the topics and merchandise we believe you might be interested in. By subscribing to our mailing lists, you accept that your personal data may be used for such purposes.

Please note that we do provide links to other sites, which may not be governed by this Privacy Policy. RS Plc is not responsible for the data protection and privacy practices within any of these other sites. We encourage you to be aware of this when you leave our site and to read the data protection and privacy statements on other websites you visit which collect your personal information.

RS Plc may also use the information we gather to notify you about important changes and alterations to the website, or offers of products, services or information that might be of particular interest to you. Your information may also be transferred to another company (based in the European Union or in a country ensuring an adequate level of protection) in the event of a sale of our company to a third party. In that event we will endeavour to ensure that your rights in respect of the processing of personal data are adequately and appropriately protected.

In processing your order, we may send your details to, and also use information from credit reference agencies and fraud prevention agencies.

All the personal information collected via this website is recorded in a secure database.

All RS Plc's employees and data processors, who have access to or are associated with the processing of personal information, are obliged to respect the confidentiality of that information.

RS Plc ensures that your personal data will not be disclosed to government institutions and authorities except if required or allowed by law.

Please note that unless encrypted, email messages sent via the internet may not be secure and could be intercepted and read by someone else. Please bear this in mind when deciding whether to include personal or sensitive information in any email messages you intend to send.

By submitting your information and ticking the requisite boxes on any order form or when subscribing to the services available on our website, you expressly consent to such use and transfer of that information to the extent permitted by applicable law. If RS Plc changes this privacy policy it will post the changes on this page. Continued use of the service will signify that you agree to any such changes. If at any time you wish to stop receiving our newsletter or any other information you may have requested from us or any other company, please email or write to the address below or click the Unsubscribe link at the bottom of any email you receive from us.  

Users 16 and under  
If you are aged 16 or under, please get your parent/guardian's permission before hand whenever you provide personal information to RS Plc's website. Users without this consent are not allowed to provide us with personal information.

Data Protection  
RS Plc will process any personal information that it collects in accordance with the [Data Protection Act 1998](http://www.opsi.gov.uk/Acts/Acts1998/ukpga_19980029_en_1). If you wish to access personal information collected from you via this website or if you have an enquiry or concern regarding the processing of personal data, please contact: [customerservices@richersounds.com](mailto:customerservices@richersounds.com)

Or write to:  
Richer Sounds Plc,  
Freepost SE5508  
London  
SE1 4BR

Under the Data Protection Act 1998, you have a right to request a copy of the information we hold about you. RS Plc will provide you with a legible copy of the personal information it holds and to which you are entitled upon request. This will be sent to you within 40 days of your request - although RS Plc almost always requires proof of your identity before supplying the information (in order to mitigate the risk of supplying information to the wrong person) and may ask you for further information to assist in locating your personal information. You may have to pay a small charge before the information is supplied.

We want to make sure that your personal information is accurate and up to date. You may ask us to correct or remove information you think is inaccurate.

Changes to our privacy policy  
We keep our privacy policy under regular review and we will place any updates on this webpage. You may wish to check this webpage every time you submit personal information to the website. This privacy policy was last updated on 18.05.12

How to contact us  
Please contact us if you have any questions about our privacy policy or information we hold about you:

By email [customerservices@richersounds.com](mailto:customerservices@richersounds.com)

Or write to us at:  
Richer Sounds Plc,  
Freepost SE5508  
London  
SE1 4BB
